<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Chief Marketing Engineer]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Chief Marketing Engineer]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:26:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AdAge: How Would You Pitch the GM Account?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>AdAge: How Would You Pitch the GM Account?</h1><p>Recently AdAge published an article which posed the question "How Would You Pitch the GM Account?" to several marketing and advertising industry executives. Many of them had some great ideas. All of them danced around two core concepts: 1. Reinvent the company brand through innovation 2. Give the people what they want. The next question: how do they do it? My answer, social media.  The other day I had dinner with a friend of mine who showed off his brand new pair of customChucks. He customized them himself at the Converse website. He chose the model, color, materials, etc.... Converse built them then shipped the shoes right to his door. Of course he paid a premium, but he got exactly what he wanted so he didn't mind. Now many of his friends are also building custom Chucks.  Compare that experience to my own when I tried to buy a new car. I'm well researched, so I knew what I wanted and what I wanted to pay when I walked in the door. But, unfortunately for me, cars are sold like cable TV subscriptions (via packages) so I needed two packages to get everything I wanted. It didn't take too long for me to find out that the two packages I wanted were both "regional", and what that meant. Apparently one package was primarily built and sold in the mid-west so, being on the east coast, it wasn't available. The other package was available, but not in conjunction with the first because the two regions typically didn't cross. In addition, they did not have any available to ship in any of the colors I hoped for. To get my car I needed a custom order for which I would, of course, have to pay a premium for a bunch of stuff I didn't want just to get the stuff I did. Needless to say, I didn't buy a car. In addition I told several people that story. They will not be buying a car either.  Imagine that. A customer comes to you, ready to buy, with cash in hand, and you lose the sale. Contrast that to several customers who knew nothing of a product but got motivated enough to buy based on the recommendation of a satisfied customer. So what does this mean to GM?  You can market a brand all you want but, in today's new media rich environment, you can't even fool some of the people some of the time. If GM want's to change their brand, they have to change their company to support the marketing. Transforming GM is not going to start with designing a new car, it's going to start with designing a new company. GM needs to treat the company is if it had failed, because it did, and go from there. Here's how:  First, admit old GM failed. Don't try to pretend it's the same company, because it's not, and nobody knows this better than the taxpayers, also known as customers. Admitting failure with accomplish two things: </p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/adage-how-would-you-pitch-the-gm-account/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">398bcc46-90bf-4164-b3f2-6c49e0de6527</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:26:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marketing In A Reputation Based Economy]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Marketing In A Reputation Based Economy</h1><p>Cred, short forstreet credit, slang foryour reputation. Defined as: commanding a level of respect due to experience in or knowledge of issues affecting those environments. Cred is traditionally associated with young, trendy people in urban areas. Today in marketing 2.0, however, it's a unit of exchange within the emerging reputation based economy. Simple terms: more cred = more value; more value = more dedicated customers; more dedicated customers = more $$. So, how's your cred?There are several different types of reputations on the Internet each impacting and being impacted by new media differently. Google, for instance, bases a site's reputation on how many other sites link to it. If you want a higher ranking, get more and better sites to link to you. In the blogosphere this is called the "echo chamber" due to the effect of syndication on rankings. Ironic to the name, however, current SEO practices focus more on driving quality traffic from other sites over just any traffic from search engines. Reputation boosting practices include hosting brand sponsored topic websites where interested individuals can gather and form a community, or social network. This accomplishes two things for the brand. First, by facilitating communication the brand creates and centralizes an active community and boosts awareness of the industry. Second, by utilizing it's own networking, the brand becomes an involved member who takes an active interest in the people gaining both credibility and awareness within the community. This is especially important for emotional industries like pharma. where people can gather and share stories. The key to successfully marketing in this environment is being the best. Your job as a marketer is to facilitate relationships and communication, then let them choose you.Slashdotandexperts-exchange, on the other hand, establish credibility in a different, yet still automated, way. They allow users to award points to other users to establish a more natural, organic, atmosphere of credibility. Much like life, in this society if you want to gain credibility you need to earn it. Once established, credibility within these networks gain you the advantages of prestige, trustworthiness, hire ranked posts, and the increased ability to improve your reputation. A segment posted by someone with high credibility, for example, will automatically rank higher than someone with less and, therefore, will have the advantage of being spotted easier and read more often thereby granting the author more credibility in the future. Much like spinning aflywheel, each positive interaction begets more positive interactions in the future. This is especially important because, unlike search engines, you cannot pay for placement; you must earn your reputation.Contrasting the previous two methods,Diggis based on a simple aggregate of users identifying a link as something they like, or "digging" it. Every day thousands of individuals see something they like enough to go out of their way to digg it. They do this because what they saw had some value to them. In this society, if you want to have credibility, you need to have value. Enough value to drive users to want to tell others about you. Credibility in this arena gains you a dedicated following of individuals who regularly derive value from your work. Those individuals tell others and your friend base grows.Social reputation also consists of all the sites that allow users to collaboratively rate and give feedback about you. Sites likeAmazonandepinionscombine a simple 5-star rating system with a short text area to facilitate individuals expressing their level of satisfaction. Where historically business need only worry about a select few critics, now everyone's a critic. Restaurants, for example, formally sought to identify the media columnists to make sure their food was hot and the order was right. Automobile manufactures only had to impress a select few magazines and reviewers. Walmart went so far as to put commercials on television which emphasized what a great place it was to work. No more. Sell a bad product on amazon and people will know. Sure it's possible to influence this initially with staged postings, but that won't last long and isn't it easier just to deliver value?The final part of your social reputation and credibility consists of everything else. This is where all the bloggers who have an experience and write about it reside and where other bloggers syndicate the post. This is where the photo of a bug in food you served falls. This is where the youTube video of your employees goofing around or slacking off fits. And this is where people can praise and recommend you. This is where people can post links to your products. This is where friends forward interesting emails. This is the culmination of your brand reputation.This is new media marketing.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/marketing-in-a-reputation-based-economy/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ae283cb2-100a-4410-84b5-ea87d1e0e9ec</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:23:41 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Media Brand Loyalty]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Media Brand Loyalty</h1><p>RecentlyEuro RSCG Worldwidereleased an article inPRWeekwhich found that last year there was a 25% increase in the number of consumers who buy based on quality over price despite nearly 75% being anxious about the economy. Further, when it comes to customer service, 80% of those surveyed said they want companies to "show a human face." Marketing 2.0 implements new media technologies that enable you to offer higher quality and personalized service to your customers. It's what they want, shouldn't you give it to them?Marketing 101: A negative customer experience results in higher attrition while a positive experience results in repeat customers and recommendations. Compounding this point: attrition rates are multiplied by the increased cost of attracting new customers while customer retention is both less expensive and worth more over the lifetime of the relationship.So how do we retain customers? Give them what they want, when they want, how they want it.What do they want?They want what you have to offer. How do I know? Because if they don't want what you have to offer, you shouldn't be marketing it to them. The days of build it and they will buy it are over. Today's economy is based onThe Long Tail, and the tail is getting longer. Consumers have preference, and they act on it. AsSeth Godinobserves in his bookMeatball Sundae, the new bell curve isn't a bell curve at all; it's more like a camel's back. The first hump represents those who want quality, the second hump represents those who want cheap. The chasm in the middle is the lack of sales to all those companies who tried to do both and ended up doing neither.The customers you want are on the first hump of the camel curve. These people have loyalty. They know what they want. They find something they like, something of value to them, and they form a relationship with it. They form a relationship, then they recommend it to others. Hump two, on the other hand, is fickle and price conscious with very little brand loyalty. Market to them if you like, but don't forget: you can't make up for negative margins with volume!When do they want it?When they're good and ready, that's when. They have an email account for their convenience, not yours. They have a phone and a mailing address for their use, not yours. There are over 172 million people subscribed to the national do not call list because they don't want to hear from you. These people took the time to go to a website and register with the government. They put effort into not hearing from you. So why do you market to them? Instead you should be concentrating on those that do want to hear from you. Your current customers and those that give you express permission to have a conversation ( a.k.a. permission marketing). A two-way communication where you are interested in them and they are interested in you. When you cease to have value, the conversation will end. Continue to have value, continue to be relevant, and continue to have loyal customers.How do they want it?That's for them to decide. It's your job to keep their opportunities open. That's New Marketing Media. That's Marketing 2.0.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/new-media-brand-loyalty/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d4c24ad1-13ca-4b22-b3f2-130e152ce06c</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:22:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marketing 2.0: Good Marketing to Great Marketing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Marketing 2.0: Good Marketing to Great Marketing</h1><p>There are a lot of good marketers out there. They are good because they consistently deliver good ROI by building good campaigns that deliver good results. Marketing 2.0 isn't about being good. It's about being great. Good, as defined byJim Collins, is the enemy of great, which is why there are a lot of good marketers and many fewer great ones. Collins's bookGood to Greatdescribes many concepts in management that relate directly to Marketing 2.0. Here's just a few to whet your appetite. You'll have to read his book for the rest :-)The Hedgehog Concept: A core idea that: drives your economic engine, you can be the best in the world at, and you are deeply passionate about. If you cannot honestly say you meet all three of these criteria, how can you expect your customers to choose you over your competitor who can? Marketing 2.0 is about bringing value to your customers by embracing the democratization of value, i.e. customers decide what is value (benefit / price) and migrate toward where the most value is. We see this over and over again with concepts like the long tail and the wisdom of crowds.Confront the brutal facts. Listen to your customers, listen to the market, and evaluate your results. Confronting the brutal facts is not giving in, it's being realistic about what you have to offer your customers. Be open to kudos, be open to criticism, and be open to change. This becomes an extremely important concept when you ask yourself what you are really offering your customers and how much you are asking from them.The Flywheel, where a small but consistent effort builds the momentum of your overall concept. Through new media marketing, a small be dedicated group is worth much more over a lifetime than a much larger motley group. New media and social networking is about working in conjunction with your customers to push that flywheel just a little faster. Momentum builds the force of your brand eventually leading it to take on a life of it's own. Malcolm Gladwell's bookThe Tipping Pointis full of examples of this.Technology as an accelerator, not a creator, of momentum. Given the potential for technology use that new media allows, this chapter is especially applicable. Seth Godin, in his bookMeatball Sundae, talks about syncing up your marketing to your business. Remember the old adage, "when all you have is a hammer everything looks like a nail"? Marketing 2.0 takes the opposite approach. Marketing 2.0 has a full tool box. It draws upon all marketing media to decide what is the best way to communicate with your customers as individuals. It is not about putting up a website. It's not about starting a blog. It's not about opening a twitter or facebook account. Any one of these things can be great if they align right with your industry, your business, and your customer. I can guarantee, however, you'll never reach my grandparents with any of them.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/marketing-20-good-marketing-to-great-marketing/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8449141f-83ef-4e22-b4f3-17e8fbfd4929</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:21:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Value of New Media Marketing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Value of New Media Marketing</h1><p>The initial appeal of online marketing was in thelong tail. With the marginal cost of the next 100,000 being extremely low, why wouldn't you? New media marketing is different. New media isn't about cost; it's about value. AsSeth Godinobserves, there are two ways for you to benefit from marketing: lower cost, or increase value. New media marketing is the latter.First, note that this is based on the concept:value = benefit / priceWhen we talk about value, we are talking about two things: value to you as a marketer, and value to your customers. Traditional mass marketing increases value to you by lowering direct cost but forfeits personalization thereby decreasing benefit, and proportionally value, to potential customers. This worked in the short term, but the sun is setting on that day. Spam filters are getting better (yes, non-permission based marketing is still considered spam by customers even if you do comply with all the can spam rules), and customers are getting smarter.New media is different. New media increases your value by increasing value to the customer. It'swin-win! New media is about cultivating a relationship with your customers, not managing it. It's about them wanting to hear more from you because you offer them value. New media is not lower your price value, it's increase your benefit value. Increasing the benefit to your customers while keeping the costs fixed raises your value which improves response rates significantly which, as a result, increases the benefit to you.The result: fewer customers are worth more. Much more. Check out my blog posts, "The New Media Marketing Matrix" and "New Media Retention Marketing", for more on that.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/the-value-of-new-media-marketing/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">cc5b0476-3b07-4cff-bfe2-9f3886c03485</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:21:19 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Media Marketing Matrix]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Media Marketing Matrix</h1><p>Today's fast pace consumer environment requires that people get what they want, when they want, and how they want it. That's where New Media marketing comes in. Traditionally you could opt to send a direct piece, an email, or place a quick phone call. New Media Marketing says what's with this "or" business? Everyone is an individual and needs to be treated as such.You don't treat one friend exactly the same as another, do you? Neither should you with your customers. New Media and Marketing 2.0 is about forming and cultivating relationships, just like you do with your friends. One of my friends is on Google Talk all day, I always know how to get in touch with him. Another is always on Facebook, while another won't be found near his computer on a sunny day. If I wanted to contact all my friends right now there's no single way to do it, but there is a best way for each of them.This is Marketing 2.0.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/new-media-marketing-matrix/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f241abbe-b61a-4903-af4f-beb690c519d4</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:20:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Media Retention Marketing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Media Retention Marketing</h1><p>In today's recession-based economy organizations are making a drastic change away from mass (acquisition) marketing toward retention marketing.Â On the consumer side, potential prospects are reeling in their spending and sliding downthe long tailby finding exactly what they want, when they want it, and for the price they want to pay.Â With acquisition marketing getting more expensive and less effective (see Zain Raj's piece on markeing focus), retention is where businesses are headed, and New Media is the tool.Some agencies simply dismiss New Media or worse, think of it as just another piece of CRM.Â They couldn't be more wrong.Â CRM is all about "managing" the relationship, and I just told you consumers don't want to be managed anymore.Â New Media is is about cultivating the relationship, not exploiting it.Â Give the consumer a reason to follow you on Twitter, join your Facebook friend list, or subscribe to your blog and that relationship will be be worth more over a lifetime than 100 new acquisitions.Â One client I have gets over a 75% click through rate on their newsletters because consumerswantto know more about what they have to offer.Why?Â New Media Marketing is designed around the concept of giving the customer what they want.Â It's about opt-in marketing.Â No, not the kind of opt-in marketing where you default the check-box at the bottom of your form.Â I'm talking about true opt-in marketing -- permission marketing.Â First, customers find you, possibly through a friend or colleague who recommended you (maybe posted your link on Facebook or twitter).Â Next, they research you.Â They check your history (the Internet never forgets), see what you've done, and see if they like it.Â And, finally, they make their own decision as to whether or not you're worth their precious and fleeting time.Â Â If you're lucky enough and you've got enough to offer you've made a friend.Now it's time to cultivate (not manage) the relationship.Â One colleague of mine follows over 150 people on Twitter and has real-time text notification of Facebook status updates sent to his iPhone via SMS.Â If you try to manage your relationship with someone like him for your own benefit you can bet he won't hesitate to not only cut you off, but also spread the word to the 150 people that are following him.Â Remember, you exist to provide value to the consumer, not the other way around.Â If you can do this profitably, then you have their permission to cultivate the relationship.The bottom line.Â Provide value, retain customers.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/new-media-retention-marketing/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2bb62700-39ab-415d-a104-f5012cabc6ef</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Media Marketing Mentality]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Media Marketing Mentality</h1><p>If the people who you market to had the option, would they choose to see your ad or ignore you all together?Â Think about this the next time you send a mass email or put together a direct piece.Â Seriously, think about it.Â If you know in advance that 97% - 99% of your "customers" are not interested in what you have to say (given a 1% - 3% conversion rate) maybe you should rethink your strategy.Â This is where New Media Marketing comes in.New Media is about giving your customers what they want.Â It's about forming amutually beneficial</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/new-media-marketing-mentality/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">871e3a44-43b3-4be8-a84c-3b24f5603ec8</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:20:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Perfect Social Networking Analogy]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>A Perfect Social Networking Analogy</h1><p>I first saw this onSeth Godin's blog. It's a perfect analogy for social networking, tipping points, spinning the flywheel, etc.... All strangers. All sharing a common interest. All starting with one dedicated person. My favorite part is right at the end when you hear a spectator asking, "how did he do that?" Can your marketing do this?</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/a-perfect-social-networking-analogy/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">47825439-1e4e-4a3b-973a-3ea92849e8b3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:19:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brand marketing vs. personal sales]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Brand marketing vs. personal sales</h1><p>Many brands would love to utilize the power of New Media, but shifting away from traditional media methodologies is not easy, especially for the older and larger agencies. Currently personal sales seems to be a much better fit for new media which raises the question, "how do we make brand marketing personal?"There's one business model in particular that I think fits the New Media mold perfectly. There's an irony here because the industries that use it seem to have positioned themselves as the late majority, or dare I say laggards, along theproduct diffusion curveof New Media technology. The model I'm talking about is that of insurance, real estate, accounting, and even pharmaceutical.Here's how it works: a parent company owns and cultivates the brand. Smaller organizations, either through licensing or branching, work independently to sell that brand. Within the child organization individuals work, mostly on commission, to build relationships and sell products offered by that brand. It's the perfect storm of New Media! Personal sales with a regional organization for product support and a parent company for brand support. Think about it. When you want an insurance agent, real estate agent, or doctor, accountant what's the first thing you do? Ask a few trusted friends for a recommendation.What if that trusted friend followed an accountant on twitter because she gives regular tips on how to save money and invest wisely? What if an insurance agent has a blog where he doles out creative ways to use insurance to better your financial situation enabling you to retire sooner and wealthier? How about a real estate agent that posts youTube videos on things to look for when evaluating a potential new home purchase and ways to inexpensively improve the value of your current home? What if these personalized sales agents market to people by providing everyday value, not just when they want something?The result: personalized service that provides value to the customer, referrals to the agent, sales to the agency, and strengthens the brand. Which, of course, leads to more referrals to the agent, sales to the agency....This is critical mass marketing. This is Marketing 2.0.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/brand-marketing-vs-personal-sales/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">841d33b9-25aa-4a77-800a-8540f9aac2e8</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:18:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>