<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Chief Marketing Engineer]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Chief Marketing Engineer]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:35:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Dark Side of Social Networking]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Dark Side of Social Networking</h1><p>As professional marketers we're always looking for new and better ways to collect information about our customers so that we may better serve them. We, for the most part, have good (read legal) intentions. Much like Disney executives who spend time in character suits within the park, I believe that it's good practice to put ourselves in the place of our customers and look at the world from their point of view. Here are some outtakes from a security newsletter,OUCH, by ANS Institute Security Newsletter for Computer Users (Volume 6, Number 7, July 2009). Take a read through and think about how simple the "simple" things you ask of your customers really are and how important a relationship really is.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/the-dark-side-of-social-networking/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9d0b8835-2d84-4c2a-bfa9-93821b442665</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:35:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Value Of An Ad Not Seen]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Value Of An Ad Not Seen</h1><p>What is the value of an ad not seen?Â Worse yet, what is the value of an ad seen but not acted upon?Â For years we as marketers have worked hard to turn the Internet into a place where ads are proactively blocked, filtered, and ignored.Â Agencies are paid to increase list size, not list quality.Â Rather than put time into properly segmenting our prospects and compiling an offering that is relevant, we collect information in any way possible and blast emails to everyone.Â This is because we choose quantity over quality thinking we're getting the best bang for our buck.Â We're not.The economics of increasing list size.Agencies are paid to increase the size of lists, increase club memberships, and collect prospect information in any way possible.Â They do this in all sorts of "creative" ways from refusing to filter out known dead leads (can't decrease the list size) to collecting information on prospects that have no interest in the productÂ Just the other day I was at theNJ State Fairand I was approached to sign up to win a smart car.Â All I had to do to enter was give them all my contact information.Â But what did they think they were going to do with this information once they had it?Â Beyond showing the increasing aggregate list counts to clients, I don't think they cared.Â The scary part is some client out there might actually think the contest was a success.Lets take a second to analyze this.Â It's possible that the agency in charge of the smart car contest made the connection that if I wanted a smart car for free, I might have an interest in buying one?Â Maybe?Â Could that be the leap in logic?Â The other option is that they are just going to sell my information to a random client, which is worse, so let's go with option one for now.Â If instead of a car they were it was a pile of money, say $16k (the value of the smart car), and they offered it to me for free, would I take it?Â Sure.Â Would I pay more than I thought it was worth for it?Â Umm, no.Â This is because it comes down to creating value for the consumer, which they made no effort to do.Â The fact is before I was asked if I would take the car for free I never considered purchasing one.Â And, after someone offered it to me for free, I still never considered purchasing one.Â I commute on NJ highways and I value my life, sorry.However, if, for instance, the same group of people had a smart car tent with information and they did there homework, it might have been an entirely different experience.Â They could have shown me a big list of all the ways the smart car could benefit me financially.Â They could have touted the benefit to the future of the environment for my son, whom I had with me.Â They could have shown me statistics and safety ratings for the car's steel passenger cage.Â They could have done a lot of things.Â Maybe then I would have been interested.Â It is at this point, only after I had a legitimate interest in the product, they could have asked if I wanted enter the smart car contest and collected my information.Â The difference here is they've laid the foundation for a relationship first.Â Â If they were really good they could have noticed I had my young son and wife with me and noted it.Â They could have casually collected information on where I work and deduced or even asked about my commute.Â They could have found out I travel a lot.Â They could have found out what was valuable to me and catered to it when they used the information they collected to market to me later.Â And when they do, I might not ignore them.Â They could have, but they did not.The value of a shirt not worn -- why arbitrary list generation doesn't work.Those who know me know I like nice shirts.Â Nice shirts cost money.Â I've been known to pay more than others consider a reasonable amount for a single shirt, but here's why.Â I'm all about marginal utility.Â When I find something I like I ask myself, "is this better then everything else I already own?".Â In fact, price means less to me than you might think.Â Marketing to me on price alone won't work.Â If I buy one shirt at Express or Guess it might cost me between $30 - $50 (or more).Â For that, I've heard, I could buy ten shirts at Walmart.Â Here's the trick: I don't want ten Walmart shirts.Â All ten of those shirts would hang in my closet for years until I cleaned them out and donated them in like-new condition.Â In the mean time I'd probably continue wearing my old shirts.Â So now I've spent good money on ten shirts I didn't wear which would be made abundantly clear when I complain to my wife that I have nothing to wear.Â Of course it no longer makes sense for me to buy a new shirt since I have ten I don't wear.See what happened there?Â The reason for not purchasing a nice shirt has become I don't wear the shirts I have.Â Given my history, it makes sense.Â It would be a waste of money for me to spend more money on a single expensive shirt because I can't afford for me not to wear it.Â It's a vicious circle of self-fulfilling prophecies.Â But what if I would wear the nice shirt?Â What then is the value of the one expensive shirt vs. the ten less expensive?Â This is the loop we've gotten ourselves into with marketing.Enter the Internet and mass marketing.CPM is the cost of touching 1000 prospects.Â It is the traditional means of normalizing ad purchases for comparison.Â C is cost, and M is the Roman numeral for 1000.Â So, by lowering the cost we lower the CPM.Â But there is another factor.Â Traditional mass marketing seeks to increase the total number of customers reached for the least amount of money.Â Since M is always 1000 in this ratio we seek out media that gives us lots of M's and a low C.Â This is where the Internet comes in.Early marketers saw the Internet as a combination of an extremely low variable cost, nearly $0 (low C), and a seemingly limitless supply of potential customers (lots of M's).Â Given such a low CPM, it made sense to take traditional advertising online with banners and mass emails.Â The result was a flood of online advertisement and subsequently the CAN SPAM Act of 2003.Â CAN SPAM is an acronym for Controlling the Assault of Non-Solicited Pornography And Marketing.Â We sold a lot of inexpensive shirts to a lot of people who were not going to wear them, and we called it marketing.Â You know how taxes are on par with death?Â Our marketing tactics and CAN SPAM put us at the moral level of unsolicited pornography.Â Not good.Customer Relationship Cultivation (CRC):That was yesterday.Â Today's new media rich environment is very different.Â Sure there are those who still use mass advertising to prey on individuals, but that's not new media marketing (despite the actual media used).Â Today we've collected a lot more information on our customers and we're learning how to use it right.Â We're learning to create value for them, not for us at their expense.Â We still talk about CPM, but we don't live by it.Â Even click-through rates (CPC -- cost per click) are becoming an antiquated statistic.Â Today's marketing is about behavior.Â It's about action.Â We understand that customers act first and purchase based on behavior, not the other way around.Â And we use new media to leverage this idea.Â Let me explain with two great examples from Zain Raj'sBehavior Firstblog:</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/the-value-of-an-ad-not-seen/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">bd978845-b4ca-4384-8bf8-16da52209549</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:35:17 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Father's Day & Independence Day]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Father's Day & Independence Day</h1><p>Father's Day, arguably the most active barbecue purchasing day of the year, is celebrated within a month of Independence Day, the most active barbecue using day of the year. Coincidence or marketing genius? You decide :-)Happy Independence Day and thanks to all those who fought for our freedom and continue to make it possible.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/fathers-day-and-independence-day/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">949f3918-e6d0-43e4-8c64-52d18002895b</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:34:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Case: Small Buisness In The Cloud]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Case: Small Buisness In The Cloud</h1><p>Kim is a friend, talented professional photographer, and owner ofTwoRoads Studio. She wanted to sell some of her prints online so she came to me to help make that happen. TwoRoads is just getting started so, like any small business, money is a primary concern. Time management is also a concern since Kim would rather be out shooting and developing photos than managing the website so the website had to be easily managed and not too technical. From a technical and marketing standpoint Kim needs a website that will look and perform professionally because sales get lost when customers have to wait for images to load, and her business is all about images. The website would also need a shopping cart and have to accept credit cards because online shoppers today expect convenient shopping and payment. What an interesting case. Here's what we did:The first hurdle we attacked was hosting. Since money is a concern we tried to keep monthly costs to a minimum. I thought about just putting her on my home server hosted over a cable modem but we wanted something more dependable than that. Yahoo! busness hosting came out to about $6.50 per month, which seemed reasonable. We also got unlimited data transfer, great for photos, and unlimited disk space. Yahoo! had several good options for expansion, like wordpress blog integration, so we settled on that.The next hurdle to clear was how Kim would manage the site. She's not a technical person and has no desire to be. Her last website had a combination of XML files she needed to edit and files she needed to resize and upload via an ftp program. Not a horrible solution, but it was a bit confusing and very time consuming to make changes. This time we decided to use Flickr to manage the photos. Kim already had an account with Flickr. She used it to post photos and show them off. It's a great application with several convenience features including drag and drop organization and simple uploading and photo resizing. The best part: Flickr has a full access php API.Flickr offered us several advantages. First, it's free. So our total costs were still only the $6.50 / month for web hosting. Second it's convenient. Kim already had an account there and was familiar with the tool. She wouldn't have to learn anything else and, at the same time, she had access to several GUI tools for the organization and manipulation of her photographs. Technically, Flickr's API gave us full access to Kim's photos and information via php. Better yet, by keeping the images on Flickr's servers we gained the hosting and response time of Flickr's diverse infrastructure because all images were served from them, not us. All we had to do was register for a free commercial development key.The next thing we needed was a shopping cart and method of accepting credit cards. Yahoo! business hosting integrated directly with paypal so this was our first choice. Right away we noticed some shortcomings. First, products had to be added to paypal's inventory system for pricing, descriptions, etc. This meant Kim would have to add her products in two places and that we'd have to find a way for the website to match the Flickr photo on the screen to the product in paypay's database. Not impossible, but not the ease of management we were looking for either. Finally, what sealed the deal, is the service offered by Yahoo! did not allow for a shopping cart. Users would only be allowed to buy one product at a time. It was time to look elsewhere for a solution.That's how we came upon google checkout. Google checkout offered everything we needed. A shopping cart system that integrated into our existing website. Core integration is done with JavaScript and layout is done with html and css. Fields and descriptors are completely customizable without having to first add the item to a google-specific inventory system. The shopping cart system linked directly into google's checkout system which allowed Kim to accept credit cards for just a small fee. Everything was customizable so we could seamlessly integrate it into the rest of Kim's website template. On top of all that, it was basically free with only a small charge based on her sales. This worked out well since, if nothing sold, she would have not fixed cost. In order for her to owe a lot she'd have to sell a lot, which is a good thing.Another advantage of using google's checkout system was the link to her analytics account. It was not an initial feature request, but I decided to create a google analytics account for her and link it to the website and checkout system. This way we are able to see all sorts of statistics on Kim's photos and it can help her determine what's going on.The final piece of the puzzle is Kim's interaction with her customers. She's a very interesting and intelligent person, so I thought she should share her stories and experiences with her customers. What better way to do that than a blog? I'd looked at both blogspot and wordpress before. Wordpress was, by far, easier to update and customize templates for. Additionally, yahoo! hosting offered a wordpress blog as a direct add on. In the end we didn't use it (opting for hosting the blog on wordpress's website), but it's still good to know we can always come back to it should we want to.Here's a summary of what we ended up with:</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/case-small-buisness-in-the-cloud/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">15172a15-7025-47ab-9c03-513313ab1997</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:34:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tappers vs. Listeners: Who's Who?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Tappers vs. Listeners: Who's Who?</h1><p>Made to Stick, a book by Chip and Dan Heath, brings about concept of tappers and listeners with respect to marketing. They contend marketers have too much information to adequately convey their message to prospective customers -- it's like an inside joke meant for the world that only we get. But what if the reverse was true? What if they are the tappers? Then we are the ones without all the information and we're missing the message the world is trying to tell us.For those of you not familiar with the tappers and listeners concept, here's an overview loosely as stated in Made to Stick: In 1990, Elizabeth Newton earned a Ph.D. in psychology at Stanford by studying a simple game in which she assigned people to one of two roles: "tappers" or "listeners." Tappers received a list of twenty-five well-known songs, such as "Happy Birthday to You" and "The StarSpangled Banner." Each tapper was asked to pick a song and tap out the rhythm to a listener (by knocking on a table). The listener's job was to guess the song, based on the rhythm being tapped. Before the listeners guessed the name of the song, however, Newton asked the tappers to predict the odds that the listeners would guess correctly. The tappers predicted the odds were 50 percent. Over the course of Newton's experiment, however, listeners guessed only 2.5 percent of the songs correctly. The tappers actually got their message across 1 time in 40, but they thought they were getting their message across 1 time in 2. As marketers there are two ways we can look at this:Way #1 (we are the tappers):Tappers are us, the marketers. We have a tune in our head but cannot sing it; we can only tap it out in monotone advertisements. Listeners are our prospective customers, the targets of our marketing. They do not have the same information we have, the tune in their head, so, with only our monotone tapping to go by, they have to guess what we're trying to say. The tune in our head makes us think we've done our job, but the reality is that monotonous tapping is simply driving our customers crazy. This is what our ego would have us believe; we've got too much information for our slow customers to keep up.Way #2 (we are the listeners):It's relatively easy for companies to lay problems with marketing on the customer. It's like walking into and interview and answering the question "what's your biggest fault" with "I'm just too darn smart for all those around me. They just don't get what I'm trying to say." We all do it. We all think we're being clear. We all think what's in our head is correct and justified. And we do this until we learn otherwise, then revise our paradigm.Social media is the otherwise; it's time to revise. Social media is about listening to our customers and finding out what they want. What matters to them? How can we better serve them? Within traditional marketing customers have a tune in their head and their trying to sing it but they can only tap (if that). Much of the time we're so busy tapping away trying to be louder than our competitors we can't even hear them. When/if we can, via letters and other means of feedback, there is no formal protocol to make real change. Customers only power, their only way to get their message through to us, the only thing we hear, is the sound of them leaving.That was traditional marketing, this is new media. New media gives voices to each of our customers. A real voice; one that we can hear. And when these voices begin to harmonize the collective volume surpasses even our marketing. They become a voice that we should be listening to and learning from, not one that we should be blocking out with the incorrect assumption we have all the information we need. Within new media there is a conversation going on. It's already taking place and we are just a guest who is welcome, like everyone else, to participate. They don't ask much. Be relevant, be courteous, and work towards the betterment of the collective participants. Sounds a lot like a good business model.New media is not a conduit for the same monotone advertising. It won't work, many have tried. In this world we are not the only tappers. No one will subscribe to the "all advertising all the time" twitter feed and, if they do, they quickly come to their senses and unsubscribe. We have to be better than that. We have to have value. And, in return for our effort, we gain insight into the collective of our customers and potential customers. We gain personal information and preferences. We gain a tune to our tapping because new media gives us the opportunity not to tune out our customers song.Be a listener, not a tapper. Listen to the customers, they have a lot to say. New media users are voluntarily generating increasingly more and better data both about themselves and each other. They tell us their likes, their dislikes, their opinions and feedback, and who their friends and family are. One facebook application alone has users creating quizes about themselves to determine how well their friends know them. They are practically segmenting themselves! It's a marketers dream come true. If only we could stop tapping.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/tappers-vs-listeners-whos-who/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">c76cb7ac-00ae-4bb0-8dd6-f61982f04105</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:34:14 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Media Marketing: The Hi-Tech Way to be Low-Tech]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Media Marketing: The Hi-Tech Way to be Low-Tech</h1><p>The whole idea behind new media and social networking is to form deeper relationships with customers which can be cultivated into a strong bond and, hopefully, brand loyalty. We use twitter, facebook, email, linkedIn, blogs, direct mail, and several other medias to stay connected to them. We spend millions to form and cultivate the relationships but, in the process, do we forget about the relationship itself?Every Saturday my town holds a farmer's market in the town hall parking lot. Local farms setup tables with fruits, vegetables, baked goods, and other wares for townies to browse and buy. Last Saturday my family and I dropped in to get a few fresh veggies for the week. While there we stopped at two farm stands, both local farms, and let the farmhands tell us what's in season and make recommendations about what we have to try. I ended up with a yellow tomato for the first time.On the way out we ran into a man walking down the road with two alpacas. Of course we had to stop. A small crowd of children and adults were there petting and taking pictures with the alpacas. The farmer told everyone their names and how much they loved attention, especially when they were hugged in pictures. While we were hugging and petting he made sure that we noted how soft and friendly they were. "Wouldn't it be nice to have something this soft with you all the time? Why don't you stop in at our market stand,Angel Wood Alpacas, and see what we have there?"Brilliant! In those few minutes we were there this man transformed us from complete strangers to falling in love with the adorable and soft alpacas. Think of the implications. From then on, anything we bought at that stand wouldn't just be an accessory, it'd be a story. It's not a scarf. It's an alpaca scarf, and I met the alpaca himself. His name is Elvis and here's a picture of me hugging him. You can meet him this Saturday at the market. Amazing! Viral marketing without a send to friend link. 100% true permission marketing. A few days later I was readingThe Wealth of Nationsand my wife asked me about it. I gave her a quick overview and she laughed but gave me some great insight to build on.We are in the midst of a new revolution. One that is bringing us backward in time. We're no longer about Adam Smith's most efficient product, we're about the relationship. Curious, I asked my wife a hypothetical question: if you could buy a better or cheaper tomato somewhere else, would you? The hands down answer: no. Why? Because of the relationship.In today's hi-tech, long tail, environments customers are about getting what they want, and they want a relationship. Theywantto be brand loyal becasue they want a brand they can count on. This is the age of information. Marketing is about making customers aware of your brand in such a way that they want to know more about it, and then making the information easily available.New is media pull marketing, not push. It's a conversation, not a megaphone. New media is relationship cultivation, not management.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/new-media-marketing-the-hi-tech-way-to-be-low-tech/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">8e36de25-5a11-4e58-b669-1aa2d27b5b3a</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:33:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Social Media: The Leader in Thought Leadership]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Social Media: The Leader in Thought Leadership</h1><p>The best and brightest minds in your industry don't work for you. Well, some might, maybe one, but the vast majority do not. This leaves you two options: one, attempt to identify, locate, and hire them -- a time-consuming and expensive proposition, assuming they are for hire -- or two, work with them to incubate and develop ideas within your industry for free.Some companies,Ideofor example, based their business model on employing the best and brightest minds. It's a good model if you can identify them, afford them, and, most importantly, they are interested in being hired. Many may not be. Many may not even be industry professionals at all. A doctor, for example, may be an innovative photographer on the side. She is not interested in leaving her job, but she'd love to talk to you about photography. She's an enthusiast, not a professional. Does this make her contribution any less great? Of course not.Innocentiveis an organization based online which carries the tag-line, "where the world innovates". They consist of over 160,000 individual innovators. Some are professionals, some are hobbyists; Innocentive doesn't care. What matters are the results. Clients come to Innocentive when their internal R&D needs help. They post real world R&D problems to Innocentive's website and get results from all the people you didn't, wouldn't, or couldn't hire directly. Innocentive's strategy is to facilitate the connection between problems and a world full of solutions. They utilizeLinus Torvaldstheory "given enough eyeballs, all bugs are shallow", and it works.Pretend for a moment you could actually attempt to employ all the best minds in your industry. All the best minds might not be looking for a job. Even if we pretend they are, in reality you probably wouldn't hire them. They might not have a decade of experience. They might not have a doctorate or even attended college. They might not dress the part, walk the walk, or talk the talk. They might not [insert qualification here] but, in social media, none of that matters. Gone are race, gender, pedigree, and qualification. What remains is simply the quality of your ideas and your work. Lead in thought and you are a thought leader.In February of 2006, for instance,Netflixhad the idea to hold a contest with a $1 million grand prize. The goal: improve on it's movie recommendation engine by 10%. Netflix supplied the data, contestants supplied the algorithms. To date there are 49552 contestants on 40738 teams from 184 different countries from which Netflix has received 41756 valid submissions. What do you think it would take to actually assemble and organize a research team that big? A lot. Which is why Netflix thinks $1 million for that kind of improvement would be a bargain. On June 27th, 2009 the winning algorithm waspostedto the Netflix leader board and the winner was not just one team. Multiple individuals formed teams and two of the leading teams organized themselves into the winning team. With no influence other than the goal and the prize these individuals took it upon themselves to organize themselves and best Netflix's professionally generated algorithm by more than 10%.So what does this mean to you? A lot. The next great idea will most likely not come from within your organization, but that doesn't mean you can't be a part of it. You need to be a part of the community, the collective, and the next great idea. Remember, social media is aboutpassion. Enthusiasts are enthusiasts because they love what they do. They love it, and you share their passion. You must, or you would not be in the industry. You must, or you must admit there is a better alternative to you. Someone with passion.The individuals who participate in social media love it so much they want to share their love by collaborating with others who also share their passion. They enjoy the work so much that they dedicate their free time to pushing harder and further into it generating ideas that further your industry. The best answers lead to better questions, and these are the people who come up with both the problems and the solutions. These are the people you should be working with. These are the people you should be talking to. These are the people utilizing social media to connect to one another.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/social-media-the-leader-in-thought-leadership/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">17227e8d-70d5-4f93-b1fc-a0eec0ea0bb3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:32:55 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Right Way to Market New Media]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Right Way to Market New Media</h1><p>New media marketing is about being the best. Offer the best information. Have the best value for your customer. When you're the best, people will follow you. When you're not, people will follow the best. The good news is, there's lots of ways to be the best. Here are 4 steps to market new media.Step 1:</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/the-right-way-to-market-new-media/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">481d24eb-0bae-4567-962a-6cba11f32d37</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:27:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why Your New Media Campaign Failed]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Why Your New Media Campaign Failed</h1><p>Passion & Greed. That's it. Those two words account for so much failure in new media, I can't even begin to tell you. But I can tell you why, and you can fix it.We've all been there. Sitting in the brainstorming meeting feeling the energy. Organizing ideas, turning ideas into goals, and building plans to meet those goals. And it's good. 500 twitter followers, 750 facebook friends and 1000 blog readers by third-quarter of next year. Plans turn to implementation, and you slowly begin notice it. We got greedy. When did it happen? How did it happen? Does this sound familiar?</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/why-your-new-media-campaign-failed/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">463978d3-4dd5-47e0-be01-b524d36ae1cd</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:26:26 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AdAge: How Would You Pitch the GM Account?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>AdAge: How Would You Pitch the GM Account?</h1><p>Recently AdAge published an article which posed the question "How Would You Pitch the GM Account?" to several marketing and advertising industry executives. Many of them had some great ideas. All of them danced around two core concepts: 1. Reinvent the company brand through innovation 2. Give the people what they want. The next question: how do they do it? My answer, social media.The other day I had dinner with a friend of mine who showed off his brand new pair of customChucks. He customized them himself at the Converse website. He chose the model, color, materials, etc.... Converse built them then shipped the shoes right to his door. Of course he paid a premium, but he got exactly what he wanted so he didn't mind. Now many of his friends are also building custom Chucks.Compare that experience to my own when I tried to buy a new car. I'm well researched, so I knew what I wanted and what I wanted to pay when I walked in the door. But, unfortunately for me, cars are sold like cable TV subscriptions (via packages) so I needed two packages to get everything I wanted. It didn't take too long for me to find out that the two packages I wanted were both "regional", and what that meant. Apparently one package was primarily built and sold in the mid-west so, being on the east coast, it wasn't available. The other package was available, but not in conjunction with the first because the two regions typically didn't cross. In addition, they did not have any available to ship in any of the colors I hoped for. To get my car I needed a custom order for which I would, of course, have to pay a premium for a bunch of stuff I didn't want just to get the stuff I did. Needless to say, I didn't buy a car. In addition I told several people that story. They will not be buying a car either.Imagine that. A customer comes to you, ready to buy, with cash in hand, and you lose the sale. Contrast that to several customers who knew nothing of a product but got motivated enough to buy based on the recommendation of a satisfied customer. So what does this mean to GM?You can market a brand all you want but, in today's new media rich environment, you can't even fool some of the people some of the time. If GM want's to change their brand, they have to change their company to support the marketing. Transforming GM is not going to start with designing a new car, it's going to start with designing a new company. GM needs to treat the company is if it had failed, because it did, and go from there. Here's how:First, admit old GM failed. Don't try to pretend it's the same company, because it's not, and nobody knows this better than the taxpayers, also known as customers. Admitting failure with accomplish two things:</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/adage-how-would-you-pitch-the-gm-account/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">398bcc46-90bf-4164-b3f2-6c49e0de6527</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:26:07 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>