<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Chief Marketing Engineer]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Chief Marketing Engineer]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:20:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Media Retention Marketing]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Media Retention Marketing</h1><p>In today's recession-based economy organizations are making a drastic change away from mass (acquisition) marketing toward retention marketing.Â On the consumer side, potential prospects are reeling in their spending and sliding downthe long tailby finding exactly what they want, when they want it, and for the price they want to pay.Â With acquisition marketing getting more expensive and less effective (see Zain Raj's piece on markeing focus), retention is where businesses are headed, and New Media is the tool.  Some agencies simply dismiss New Media or worse, think of it as just another piece of CRM.Â They couldn't be more wrong.Â CRM is all about "managing" the relationship, and I just told you consumers don't want to be managed anymore.Â New Media is is about cultivating the relationship, not exploiting it.Â Give the consumer a reason to follow you on Twitter, join your Facebook friend list, or subscribe to your blog and that relationship will be be worth more over a lifetime than 100 new acquisitions.Â One client I have gets over a 75% click through rate on their newsletters because consumerswantto know more about what they have to offer.  Why?Â New Media Marketing is designed around the concept of giving the customer what they want.Â It's about opt-in marketing.Â No, not the kind of opt-in marketing where you default the check-box at the bottom of your form.Â I'm talking about true opt-in marketing -- permission marketing.Â First, customers find you, possibly through a friend or colleague who recommended you (maybe posted your link on Facebook or twitter).Â Next, they research you.Â They check your history (the Internet never forgets), see what you've done, and see if they like it.Â And, finally, they make their own decision as to whether or not you're worth their precious and fleeting time.Â Â If you're lucky enough and you've got enough to offer you've made a friend.  Now it's time to cultivate (not manage) the relationship.Â One colleague of mine follows over 150 people on Twitter and has real-time text notification of Facebook status updates sent to his iPhone via SMS.Â If you try to manage your relationship with someone like him for your own benefit you can bet he won't hesitate to not only cut you off, but also spread the word to the 150 people that are following him.Â Remember, you exist to provide value to the consumer, not the other way around.Â If you can do this profitably, then you have their permission to cultivate the relationship.  The bottom line.Â Provide value, retain customers.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/new-media-retention-marketing/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2bb62700-39ab-415d-a104-f5012cabc6ef</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Media Marketing Mentality]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Media Marketing Mentality</h1><p>If the people who you market to had the option, would they choose to see your ad or ignore you all together?Â Think about this the next time you send a mass email or put together a direct piece.Â Seriously, think about it.Â If you know in advance that 97% - 99% of your "customers" are not interested in what you have to say (given a 1% - 3% conversion rate) maybe you should rethink your strategy.Â This is where New Media Marketing comes in.  New Media is about giving your customers what they want.Â It's about forming amutually beneficial</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/new-media-marketing-mentality/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">871e3a44-43b3-4be8-a84c-3b24f5603ec8</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:20:09 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Perfect Social Networking Analogy]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>A Perfect Social Networking Analogy</h1><p>I first saw this onSeth Godin's blog. It's a perfect analogy for social networking, tipping points, spinning the flywheel, etc.... All strangers. All sharing a common interest. All starting with one dedicated person. My favorite part is right at the end when you hear a spectator asking, "how did he do that?" Can your marketing do this?</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/a-perfect-social-networking-analogy/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">47825439-1e4e-4a3b-973a-3ea92849e8b3</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:19:39 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brand marketing vs. personal sales]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Brand marketing vs. personal sales</h1><p>Many brands would love to utilize the power of New Media, but shifting away from traditional media methodologies is not easy, especially for the older and larger agencies. Currently personal sales seems to be a much better fit for new media which raises the question, "how do we make brand marketing personal?"There's one business model in particular that I think fits the New Media mold perfectly. There's an irony here because the industries that use it seem to have positioned themselves as the late majority, or dare I say laggards, along theproduct diffusion curveof New Media technology. The model I'm talking about is that of insurance, real estate, accounting, and even pharmaceutical.Here's how it works: a parent company owns and cultivates the brand. Smaller organizations, either through licensing or branching, work independently to sell that brand. Within the child organization individuals work, mostly on commission, to build relationships and sell products offered by that brand. It's the perfect storm of New Media! Personal sales with a regional organization for product support and a parent company for brand support. Think about it. When you want an insurance agent, real estate agent, or doctor, accountant what's the first thing you do? Ask a few trusted friends for a recommendation.What if that trusted friend followed an accountant on twitter because she gives regular tips on how to save money and invest wisely? What if an insurance agent has a blog where he doles out creative ways to use insurance to better your financial situation enabling you to retire sooner and wealthier? How about a real estate agent that posts youTube videos on things to look for when evaluating a potential new home purchase and ways to inexpensively improve the value of your current home? What if these personalized sales agents market to people by providing everyday value, not just when they want something?The result: personalized service that provides value to the customer, referrals to the agent, sales to the agency, and strengthens the brand. Which, of course, leads to more referrals to the agent, sales to the agency....This is critical mass marketing. This is Marketing 2.0.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/brand-marketing-vs-personal-sales/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">841d33b9-25aa-4a77-800a-8540f9aac2e8</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:18:51 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Flip Side of New Media]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Flip Side of New Media</h1><p>In discussing new media marketing most of the questions I get widdle down to "how do I get my message out?" This is a very Marketing 1.0 perspective on Marketing 2.0. We're not going to talk about that. What we are going to discuss is all the other, non-billboard-like, uses of new media.The first thing to note is that simply creating a blog, twitter, youTube, or facebook account does not mean you are instantly utilizing the power of marketing 2.0. It takes a lot more than that. One of the highest hurdles for traditional marketing folk to pass is making the mental transition from one-to-many (mass) marketing, past one-to-one (customized) marketing, to many-to-many (social) marketing.Many of us get caught-up at that second phase, one-to-one, or even one-to-many, because we have a hard time releasing control of our message. We are convinced we know what the consumer wants. In his best selling book,The Tipping Point, Malcolm Gladwell describes many ideas that take on a life of their own. He calls this the tipping point, boiling point, or reaching critical mass. This book was a NYT best seller, so millions of you bought it, read it, and said, "wouldn't that be great". Yet, for some reason, you still refuse to relinquish control to the social.New media is social media. Pretend, for a moment, you attend a social event every day. At that party is a very interesting person but they only ever talk, never listen. At first you may find them intriguing, so you stick around and listen. The second week is a bit more frustrating so you begin to branch out (after all, this is a social event). By the second month you're warning newcomers to steer clear of that arrogant windbag. Listen, and there is a lot you can learn.Listen to the people. Croudsourcingis shorthand for the trend of leveraging the mass collaboration enabled byWeb 2.0technologies to achieve business goals or, more succinctly, distributed problem-solving and production model. By now everyone has heard the Henry Ford quote, "if I had asked the people what they wanted, they would have said a faster horse", but Ford, of course, did not have access to products likeIBM's Jam softwarewhich facilitated Innovation Jam 2006, the worlds largest online brainstorming (croudsourcing) session. Since then they've used the application to help impact issues of urban sustainability, hunger, environmental concerns, health, and quality of life. IBM listened to the people. Then they invested $100 million in 10 new projects that resulted.Google did something similar withProject 10^100(pronounced "Project 10 to the 100th") by calling for ideas from around the globe which change the world by helping as many people as possible. The neat part about this, I thought, is that you only need the idea, not the skill to implement nor the knowledge to make it work. Just the idea. To make it all happen Google set aside $10 million to finance the winning idea. The winner, by the way, will be picked by you. With over 150,000 submissions, Google is going to change the world by listening.Listen to the clients. If you're in business, then you've got clients. The CEO of my company (Zain Raj, Euro RSCG Discovery), for example, has ablog. If you think you might want to do business with us and want to know what he's thinking, there it is. Likewise, if we want to win business, the CEO of a potential client might also have a blog. Read it. The company may have a newsletter. Sign up for it. Take an active and real (they'll know if it's not) interest in your clients and what they want. Cultivate the relationship. Then, and only then, ask what you can do to help.New media is social media. Listen, or risk being ignored.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/the-flip-side-of-new-media/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5596cb06-69e1-4c96-97ea-acd2aa65710c</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:18:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Best Day to Send an Email]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>The Best Day to Send an Email</h1><p>Browsing the message boards the other day I saw someone posted the question: "what's the best day to send an email campaign?". Immediately, the fundamental flaw with this question jumped out at me, i.e. it does not take into account the individuality of the customers you are marketing to. In fact, such a broad question doesn't even take into account the preferences of the segment or, for all I know, the preferences of any single country. Marketing 2.0 is about knowing your customers and cultivating relationships. It's about catering to their needs as individuals, not as segments, and certainly not as "the best day to send an email".Several people replied to the question with valid statistics on opens (Friday), click-throughs (Sunday -- but with poor opens), and overall performance (mid-week). Based on the variety of these replies I imagine the poster is no better off now than before. Basically the answers didn't say anything. This is because the best day to contact your customers is the best day for your customers asindividuals. New media marketing is about cultivating the relationship with each of your customers. Given this, why stop at the best day to send an email? What about the best time? How about breaking away from emails and utilizing the best method of contact?As an individual, I have a schedule and so do you. If, for instance, I wanted to get in touch with you right now the best way might be to post to this blog since that is was you are reading. You could, however, be reading this on either a mobile device or a computer. You may be at work, you may be at home, you may be on a train between the two, or you could be someplace completely different. You may have twitter pinging you with an SMS, or you may follow my RSS. You could have found a link on a message board, or you may have linked to this blog in an email from a friend, or maybe this post is syndicated. An hour from now the best way to contact you may be completely different than it is right now. Today may be the best day for you to receive an email, but is an email really the best way to contact you today? Right now?The point is think about how you got here. Now think about all the ways that everyone else may have gotten here. Now ask yourself, is there really abestway to get here or only different ways? Some of the more literal types might say "yes, there is a 'best' way", so I ask you, how good is it really? This isThe Long Tailof communicating with your customers where the sum total return of the best way is no where close to the sum total return of all the other ways. As a marketer, why would you give all that up in pursuit of "the best day"?This is a new age of marketing where we are not restricted to "the best day". This is Marketing 2.0 where we think in terms of the best hour of the best day using the best method to cultivate the relationship with you as an individual.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/the-best-day-to-send-an-email/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">eed57ec2-bbf1-4abd-9c1d-fd9430b93831</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:18:03 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Media: Market Development or Penetration?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>New Media: Market Development or Penetration?</h1><p>In his latest blog post,Whether or which, Seth Godin makes an excellent reference to the strength of new media in expanding market share vs. expanding the market in general. I'd like to take his concept a step further by contending a hidden market exists which, when tapped, acts like market expansion with all the benefits of market penetration. And new media is the perfect way to gain access to it.Within the Marketing 1.0 paradigm market penetration concentrates on bringing new customers into your existing market and market development looks to convince existing members of the market to use your product. But what if I told you there was a gray area of your market lurking in the shadows? One that's made up ofindividualswho exist in your market and would use your product, but your Marketing 1.0 tactics have not reached. There is. Do not misread! This is not about "reaching the unreachable". It is about leveraging the strengths of new media to reach thoseindividualscurrently in your market beyond the reach of Marketing 1.0, but perfectly poised to be touched by Marketing 2.0.I'm talking about the new "preferred method of contact". Don't send me an email and expect me to read it, even if it does have my name personalized at the top. I get many of these every day, and I read none of them. Do @ message me on twitter. If you're message is relevant and interesting, I'll RT to all my friends and you'll get more than you bargained for. Create interesting and relevant information consistently and I'll follow you at your twitter account. Want me to opt-in to your newsletter? Instead, how about a Facebook profile I can become a fan of? Skittlesdid a great job with their profile and now I see updates right next to the status of my best friends and family, along with nearly 900,000 other people. That's 900,000individualswho said, "yes Skittles, you may market to me". That's a Marketing 1.0 value of 30,000,000 given the traditional 97% failure rate of mass emails!What's left? Plenty. How about a blog? Have something relevant and timely to say and customers will listen... but only if you listen too. Make sure comments are enabled! Think of a mass email as shouting at your customers. Now consider a blog to be a conversation. Which would you prefer? Customers are people to, and they don't like being talked at or marketed to any more than you do... possibly less. Remember, you're not relevant and interesting until your customers say you are. And when they do, or they tell you how you could be, make sure you're listening. A blog will open you up to both syndication and subscribers. It won't be read by the unreachable, it will be read by the reachable you've been missing until now.Want more? Take everything we've talked about and go mobile! Send your message straight to the iPhone with an application. WSJjust opened up previously paid content so iPhone users could see it. Amazon'sKindleis a great innovation that made libraries mobile, now they did it again with Kindle for iPhone. Make sure your website has an easily navigated web version. Google has done a great job with theirgmail,reader, andsearchsites. Text message, tweet, and have mobile friendly templates on your outbound emails. After all, when you finally do touch theseindividuals, make sure they get it, make sure they open it, and, if you get that far, certainly make sure they can read it.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/new-media-market-development-or-penetration/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">cc6a75a5-c40a-4d65-8d4a-16e25029b85c</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:17:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Book Review: Good to Great]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Book Review: Good to Great</h1><p>Jim Collins. (2001).Good to Great. HarperBusinessJim Collins and his team did a great job of breaking down both business and leaders into factors that helped make them successful.Â Though Collins markets it as a business book I believe, like those of Covey, the theories in this book will serve you well in both business and personal aspects of your life.Â This book was used as a text in my MBA studies at Fairleigh Dickinson Universityâ€™s Silberman College of Buisness, a nationally top ranking entrepreneurship school.Â As such Iâ€™ve engaged in many hours of discussion with both students and seasoned professionals about the merits and short-comings of this book.First, Iâ€™ll start with where it comes up short since everyone loves that and Iâ€™d prefer to finish on a positive note anyway.Â Some people feel that Collinsâ€™s findings just arenâ€™t possible to implement in real world work environments.Â Others argue that most of this material just doesnâ€™t apply to anyone thatâ€™s not a senior executive in the organization.Â Last, and my favorite, is the rational that success, especially in these companies, is random and luck based.Â I contend theyâ€™re all wrong, and Iâ€™ll tell you why.Â The only criticism of this book I do accept is Collinsâ€™s criteria for a successful company is purely financial, which I donâ€™t agree with, but he does address his reasoning right at the beginning.Â I understand why he had to do it, but I still donâ€™t agree with it.To those who argue Collinsâ€™ methods are not implementable in the real world I say quit arguing the metaphors and learn from the principles.Â Try not to get stuck duplicating the examples Collins uses in the book, they are just examples.Â Read between the lines and just pull out what heâ€™s trying to sayâ€¦ â€œfirst whoâ€¦â€, â€œThe Hedgehog Conceptâ€, â€œThe Flywheelâ€, and, if you have the audiobook, pay close attention to the student question in the epilogue.Â These are simple concepts that can have a great impact on you, your organization, and your career.Â I contend that each and every one of the theories in this book can be implemented in business at all levels, not just at the top, as well as everyday life.Â I believe you can be a level five leader in life, not just in business.Â The bookLeadership and Self-Deception, by The Arbinger Institute, is a great book to emphasize this point.And, finally, for anyone that feels success is random and/or we canâ€™t break it down into a set of rules or principles Iâ€™d recommend reading Talebâ€™sThe Black Swan, (a great book btw) which might make you feel better about yourself.Â Iâ€™d also recommendOutliersby Gladwell, another book which does in-depth research into success.Â Look specifically at the 10,000 hour rule and see how well it fits with Collinsâ€™s Flywheel concept.Now for the pros of this book.Â There are too many to list.Â Collinsâ€™s principles of level five leadership, the fly wheel, the doom loop, build-up to break-through, etc., etc., and so on, and so on are all very good points.Â Again, these principles donâ€™t just apply to business, they apply to life.Â Iâ€™m currently a technology marketing professional, but not a sr. executive.Â Build-up to break-through and the flywheel concept are just two great ways Iâ€™ve made a difference in my organization from the bottom up.Â Iâ€™m also an entrepreneur and own my own business and one of the best things I found about Good To Great was The Hedgehog concept and how it applies to Gladwellâ€™s 10,000 hour rule.Overall a good read with great theories.Â As always the metaphors and examples can be argued until youâ€™re blue in the face, but if you attempt to do that then youâ€™ve already missed whatâ€™s important about this book.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/book-review-good-to-great/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">25da12dd-0296-48f0-865d-9f45e7c4affa</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:17:23 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Book Review: Leadership and Self Deception]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Book Review: Leadership and Self Deception</h1><p>The Arbinger Institute. (2000).Leadership and Self-Deception: Getting Out of the Box. San Francisco: Berrett-Hoehler.The Arbinger Institute did a great job of explaining their theory as will serve you well in both business and personal aspects of your life.Â It was a very easy read and has a lot of potential to make you think about yourself and how you relate to both the world and your job.Â This book was used as a text in my MBA studies at Fairleigh Dickinson Universityâ€™s Silberman College of Buisness, a nationally top ranking entrepreneurship school.Â As such Iâ€™ve engaged in many hours of discussion with both students and seasoned professionals about the merits and short-comings of this book.Â Iâ€™ve also recommended this book to both friends and family.First, the criticism.Â This is a love it or hate it book.Â I loved it, my wife hated it.Â Some in our discussion group loved it, others hated it.Â You might love it, you might hate it so sorry, I canâ€™t offer you more on that.Â Of those who hated hereâ€™s what they didnâ€™t like:Â 1. It was not well researched.Â Itâ€™s just a story with no data or anything hard to back it up.Â 2. The story is an obvious fabrication used to make a point, which it is, but I can get past that and listen to the point.Â 3. This book is written like a teacher speaks to third graders.Â 4.Â Itâ€™s just not realistic.Â Itâ€™s a recipe to be stepped on and taken advantage of.Â For this to work the entire organization would have to buy in.Â 5. The end of the book is an obvious marketing ploy to bring business into the Arbinger Institute.Now, the rebuts and the positives.Â 1 & 2. Forget the story.Â The story is a medium for the lesson, and the lesson is a good one.Â The research did not go into the story, the research went into the lesson.Â 3.Â I agree that the book seems like itâ€™s written by a third grade teacher, but I appreciate it.Â At first I did not but then I realized that I was actually retaining the information.Â Itâ€™s very useful if you are going to be putting the book down and picking it up again later.Â If not, itâ€™s just a quick read.Â 4.Â The whole lesson is greater than the sum of its parts.Â This is one of those books youâ€™ll have to read four or five times, have a friend read it, discuss it a bit, and then have a dream about it before you get that a-ha moment.Â You'll fight the concepts at first, everyone seems to, but when it comes itâ€™s worth it and all things fall into place.Â 5.Â As for the blatant marketing, skip the last chapter (24), youâ€™ll feel better about the book.I like this book and plan on reading it at least once per year.Â Itâ€™s a quick read that will help center you in life and in leadership.Â It goes very well with the concept of Level 5 Leadership from Collinsâ€™s bookGood to Greatand Coveyâ€™s7 Habits.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/book-review-leadership-and-self-deception/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">91208c80-efb4-4de3-a24d-a45cea3ace25</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:15:27 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Book Review: Made To Stick]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>Book Review: Made To Stick</h1><p>Chip Heath & Dan Heath. (2007).Made to Stick. Random House.</p></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/chief-marketing-engineer/book-review-made-to-stick/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">16b07042-846c-4955-bb7b-cc16054ed027</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 02:14:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>